Evan Gillogley

Senior Front End Engineer

evanjmg@gmail.com © 0858251023 (*)

@evanjmg 🌘

evanjmg.com

I'm a passionate front end engineer who builds scalable web and mobile applications. In the last 5 years, I've built large-scale websites for millions of customers and also developed high fidelity React Native mobile applications. I'm looking for a company that cares for the customer, values great design, and encourages innovation in Dublin.

SKILLS

Highly Skilled in

- TypeScript
- Angular 8/9, RXJS
- · React, React Native, Redux
- Electron & Chrome Extensions
- CodeceptJS/Appium/Protractor

Comfortable with

- Express, Docker, Mongo, Swagger, Sequelize
- Writing in Ruby
- Sketch & Omnigraffle
- Building Native Modules for React Native – some Java

Interested in

- Finding the best CI/CD release process
- New Architectural and Abstraction paradigms
- Ensuring a smooth product delivery process from design to release

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

June 2019 - Present

Ryanair (<u>https://www.ryanair.com</u>)

- Core contributor to new Flight Selection, Search, and Passenger flow for web mobile/desktop.
- Leads 2-3 releases a week and actively contributes to common components.
- Tech Stack: Angular 8/9, Ngrx Effects, Lerna, Ramda, Marble Testing, CodeceptJS

Lead Front End Developer

June 2018 - June 2019

Velocity Black (https://velocity.black)

- Lead developer for Front-end web and React Native development.
- Contributed frequently to open source and give talks on React Native and end-to-end web and mobile testing.
- Sometimes contributed to backend development (SQL, Express, Swagger, Kubernetes).

Front End Developer

June 2016 - June 2018

Velocity Black (https://velocity.black)

- Worked in Agile and Kanban environments with teams up to 20 people
- Introduced React, React Native, Chrome Extensions, and Electron into Velocity's tech stack
- Built various component libraries in Angular and React all in TypeScript

Lead Full Stack Web Developer

October 2015 to June 2016

Great Little Place (Not longer in operation – 100k+ users)

- Built their AngularJS site from scratch
- Made over a dozen REST endpoints with Postgres Search and PostGIS.
- Wrote many web scrapers in Ruby and JavaScript
- Implemented automated Python tasks into CMS and improved the speed of the CMS.

RECENT PROJECTS

Ryanair Flight Select & Edit Search

July 2019 - Present

- Migrated home page search into a common component to be reused and lazy loaded in flight select.
- Redesigned Fare Selection for mobile
- Created Mobile Sidebar component for all pages.

Velocity Black iOS/Android

February 2018 - June 2019

Lead engineer on the React Native product of Velocity Black, a premium membership-only concierge app that costs over \$2k a year. App is still used my thousands of millionaires a day. <u>iOS Store / Android</u>

- Stack: Redux Observable, TypeScript, & Firebase, Fast lane
- Wrote a full suite E2E tests to test all aspects of the application (Applium, Cucumber, Typescript)
- Wrote a few native modules in Java and Objective C for the application

EDUCATION

MSc International Marketing | GCU London (1st – Distinction)

Jan 2015 - May 2016

Web Development Immersive | General Assembly

June 2015 - Sept 2015

University of California Santa Barbara

Sept 2010 - Dec 2013

Graduated with a Bachelor of Arts in Economics and Film & Media Studies, 3.63 GPA (UK eq. 2:1)